Finding Aid for Department of History (University of Michigan) Senior Honors Theses
Bentley Historical Library
- Senior Honors Theses
  - 2005
    - Mobley, W. Patrick Disease, Rhetoric, and Action: Cholera in Detroit, 1832 and 1834, [84] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Cholera, Detroit (Mich.))
    - Radke, Heather 'This Machine Kills Fascists,' Interactions Between Politics and Folk Music, [85] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Canterbury House (Ann Arbor, Michigan), Communism – United States, Folk Music, International Workers of the World, Labor and labor classes, Lomax, Alan, 1915-2002, Protest movements – United States, University of Michigan – Students – Political activity)
    - Watkins, Ryan An Education for All Our Children, An Urban Case Study of the Life Adjustment Movement, [86] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Detroit Public Schools, Education, High Schools – Curricula, Labor and labor classes)
  - 2006
    - Bullock, Amanda A New Working Class: Students for a Democratic Society and the United Auto Workers in the Sixties, [87] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America., Labor and labor classes, Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.), University of Michigan – Students – Political activity.)
    - Gierada, Tracy A Manifest Tragedy: American Expansion and the Lumbering Frontier of Michigan, [88] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Lumber and lumbering – Environmental aspects, United States – Territorial Expansion)
    - Retzloff, Tim "Just Unheard Of": Suburbanization and the Shaping of Gay and Lesbian Communities in Metro Detroit, [89] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Gays – Michigan – Metropolitan Detroit, Homosexuality – Social Aspects – Michigan – Detroit, Suburbs – Michigan – Detroit Metropolitan Area – History)
  - 2007
    - Baghdadchi, Iden Assessing the Aftermath: Post 9/11 Discrimination in Arab Detroit; National and Local Perspectives on Arab and Muslim Americans in Society, [90] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Arab Americans – Michigan, Detroit (Mich.), Immigrants – Michigan – Detroit, September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001)
    - Carmichael, Karen A. Americanization and Mexican Immigrants: Racism and Citizenship in Conflict in 1920s Detroit, [91] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Immigrants – Michigan – Detroit, Detroit (Mich.), Mexican-Americans--Michigan--Detroit)
    - Mallen, Elliott Urban Insurgency on the Great Lakes: Civil Rights and White Flight in Benton Harbor, Michigan, [92] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Benton Harbor (Mich.) – Race relations, Race relations)
    - Zajac, Jonathan Alexander The Importance of Being Polish: The Complex Interactions of Community Identity and Race in Hamtramack's Postwar Development, [93] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Detroit (Mich.), Hamtramack (Mich.), Immigrants – Michigan – Detroit, Polish-Americans)
  - 2008
    - Davidson, Jeremy AIDS at the University of Michigan: 1985-1990, [94] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: AIDS, University of Michigan – History)
  - 2009
    - Kellett, Maureen Fixture of a Changing Landscape: A History of Detroit's Michigan Central Station, [95] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Detroit (Mich.), Detroit (Mich.) – Politics and government, Michigan Central Railroad Depot (Detroit, Mich.) Railroads., City Planning – Michigan)
    - Williamson, David Against the Grain: The Word of God Community from 1967-1987, [96] (Box 5)
      (Subject Terms: Ann Arbor (Mich.), Word of God Movement, Religious Movements,)
  - 2010
    - Balabuch, Andrew R. To Run and Play: Resistance and Community at the Mt. Pleasant Indian Industrial School, 1892-1933, [97] (Box 6)
      (Subject Terms: Indians of North America – Michigan – Education, Mount Pleasant Indian Industrial School)
    - Domin, Sarah Accidental Destinations: The Story of the Senegalese Immigrant Community in Detroit, [98] (Box 6)
      (Subject Terms: Senegalese Americans – Michigan, Immigrants – Michigan – Detroit, Detroit (Mich.))
  - 2011
    - Stefanick, Adam Personality and Power in the Ford Motor Company Hierarchy: The Story of Harry Bennett, 1916-1945, [99] (Box 6)
      (Subject Terms: AIDS, Bennett, Harry Herbert, 1892-1979; Ford Motor Company)
Additional 2006-2011 theses and Senior Honors theses dated 2012-[ongoing] are available through the Deptartment of History in Deep Blue, the University of Michigan digital repository, as part of the Honors Theses (Bachelor's) collection.
Subject Index to History Honors Theses
The numbers in this index refer to the number in brackets [] following each thesis.
Academic freedom
19
Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921
29
Afro-Americans -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor
33
Afro-Americans -- Michigan -- Battle Creek
70
Afro-Americans -- Michigan -- Detroit
27, 62, 65, 69, 71, 74, 76, 78
Afro-Americans -- Michigan -- Flint
72, 80
Agriculture
21
AIDS
94
Air - Pollution -- Law and legislation -- United States
38
Ann Arbor (Mich.)
3, 8, 13, 23, 28, 34-a, 42, 96
Ann Arbor (Mich.) -- Schools
34-a
Arab Americans -- Michigan
90
Automobile industry and trade
10, 24, 47, 79
Benton Harbor (Mich.) -- Race relations
92
Brown, Henry Billings, 1836-1913
81
Canterbury House (Ann Arbor, Michigan)
85
Child abuse
4
Child development
25
Cholera
84
City Planning -- Michigan
67, 70, 76, 77, 95
College Students -- Political Activity
83
Communism -- Michigan
75
Communism -- United States
85
Cooperative societies -- Michigan
45
Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1891-1979.
16
Crematoriums
8
Death
8, 37
Democratic Party (Mich.)
63
Demography
14
Detroit (Mich.)
2, 5, 12, 27, 34, 46, 47, 53, 55, 58, 62, 65, 66, 71, 73, 74, 84, 90, 93, 95
Detroit (Mich.) -- Politics and government
12, 62, 71, 74, 95
Detroit Public Schools
86
Detroit Urban League
27
Dieterle, Enoch, 1865-1929
13
Dodge Revolutionary Union Movement
61
Elections -- United States -- 1968
20
Education
39, 73, 86
Fertility, Human
14, 17
Filipino Americans
66
Fiscal policy
59
Folk Music
85
Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006
38
Ford, Henry, 1863-1947
35, 82
Ford Motor Company
79
Gays -- Michigan -- Metropolitan Detroit
89
General Motors Corporation
10, 24, 72, 80
Hamtramack (Mich.)
93
Henry Ford Museum and Greenfield Village -- History
82
High Schools -- Curricula
86
Hill Auditorium (University of Michigan)
60
Historical Museums
82
Homosexuality -- Social Aspects -- Michigan -- Detroit
89
Housing -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor
3
Immigrants -- Michigan -- Detroit
53, 79, 90, 91, 93
Indians of North America -- Michigan -- Claims
6
International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America.
26, 32, 34, 87
International Workers of the World
11, 85
Irish, American -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor
42
Jews, American -- Michigan -- Detroit.
5, 35, 55
Kindergarten
54
Labor and labor classes
11, 26, 32, 34, 61, 72, 85, 86, 87
Lakewood Crematory
8
Lomax, Alan, 1915-2002
85
Ludington (Mich.)
17
Lumber and lumbering -- Environmental aspects
88
Mason County (Mich.)
17
Merrill-Palmer Institute
25
Michigan -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
63, 69
Michigan Central Railroad Depot
95
Michigan State Anti-slavery Society
64
Michigan. Supreme Court
68
Multi-cultural education
58
New Deal, 1933-1939
28
Newspapers
21, 43
Northwest, Old
6
Pingree, Hazen Smith, 1840-1901
12
Planned Parenthood -- Michigan
50
Polar Bear Expedition, 1918-1919
51
Presidents -- United States -- Elections -- 1840
40
Presidents -- United States -- Elections -- 1968
20
Pro-life movement
64
Protest movements -- United States
83, 85
Quarantine -- Michigan -- Untied States
84
Race relations 1860-1870.
69
Railroads.
95
Recombinant DNA -- Research.
48
Recombinant DNA -- Research.
48
Religious movements.
96
Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970.
32
Right to Life of Michigan
63
Romney, George W., 1907-1995
20, 34
Saline Valley Farms (Saline, Mich.)
45
September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001
90
Sligh, Charles Robert, 1906-1997
34-d
Soviet Union -- History -- Allied intervention, 1918-1920
51
Stone, Ralph, 1868-1956.
41
Strikes and lockouts
7, 34, 47
Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.)
9, 23, 87
Student-administrator relationships
57
Suburbs -- Michigan -- Detroit Metropolitan Area -- History
89
Sunrise Cooperative Farm Community.
45
Teachers
15, 54
Techno music
65
Trade-unions
11, 26
Undertakers and undertaking
13
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
44
United States -- Supreme Court
81
United States -- Territorial Expansion
88
University of Michigan -- Admissions
52
University of Michigan -- Athletics
33, 49
University of Michigan -- Band
18
University of Michigan -- History
18, 19, 30, 31, 33, 36, 43, 48, 49, 52, 56, 57, 94
University of Michigan -- Law School
56
University of Michigan -- Minority students
33
University of Michigan -- Research
48
University of Michigan -- Students -- Political activity.
43, 75, 85, 87
University of Michigan -- Wars, emergencies, etc. (World War, 1939-1945)
30
Upper Peninsula (Mich.)
21
Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1884-1951
1, 34-b
Washtenaw County (Mich.)
4, 14
Washtenaw County (Mich.) -- Politics and government, 1840
40
Women -- History
7, 14, 15, 37, 39, 44, 49, 56, 78
Word of God Movement.
96